Guide to the Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics photographs, 1950-2005.
Laboratory for Elementary Particle Physics photographs
- Photographs (Box 7-10)
  - #10678-6 10 GeV Assembly in Tunnel, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Magnet Fabrication, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Argonne National Lab. Photos “Measurements of Magnetic Effects of Vacuum Chambers”, 1967-10-08 (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - Cutaway Drawing of the end of a 10 GeV syn. magnet (Box 9, Folder 24-26)
  - #6871-26-6 Person on bicycle in tunnel (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6711-3-12 Steering coil apparatus, R. Litauer (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-3-15A Person with shop drawing (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-10-3 Experimental Hall L0, C Chaffey (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-21-6, -19-35 Magnet Lamination J.Fuller,D.Edwards (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-20-2, -3 Survey, Wm. Woodward (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-19-9, -12, -27, -28 same as above (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-27-17 Tunnel, H. Edwards (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-27-13 Synchrotron Magnet (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-27-6 Vacuum Chamber (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-25-15, -16 Synchrotron Magnet, J. Fuller (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-24-20, -21, -24 Vacuum Chamber (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-22-24, -25 Synchrotron magnet table 187 (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-2-29, #6871-11-20A, #6871-5-16, -27, -28 IBM 1800 computer (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-5-12 Circuit board (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-5-9 Circuit drawing (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-5-7 Circuit in small box (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-4-12A Control Desk, B. McDaniel (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-3-7A Control desk oscilloscope (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-2-9 Circuit board closeup (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-24 Synchrotron experiment patch panel wiring (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-8-19 Synchrotron experiment and person (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-20 Synchrotron experiment, E. Nordberg (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-12 Control Room, E. vonBorstal (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-4 Soldering a circuit board (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-3 Assembly of a circuit panel (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-1-2 Measuring apparatus with person (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-7-14 Synchrotron water interconnections (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-7-10 Assembling apparatus in tunnel (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-6-28 Linac E. vonBorstal and two others (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-11-9 Fish eye view of control room (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-9-22 Transformer pad, C. Chaffey (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-32-11, -13 Control room and person (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-29-16 Fish eye view of control room (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-28-34 Interconnect wiring, H. Edwards, R. Bower (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-28-8 Interconnect wiring and person (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-6-3, -8, -22 Synchrotron tunnel RF, E. vonBorstal (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871-7-18, -22 Linac E vonBorstal and person (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - #6871--22-21 Klystron in tunnel with two people (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - Argonne Nat. Lab. Neg. #1383297 October 18, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Two racks of electronics “Multiverter” (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Cornell Univ. Photo #6832-3-36A Interlock racks, C. Chaffey (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #6871-29-3 RF Control racks and technician (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #68771-19-19 Oscilloscope and RF control (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #10678-8 Control electronics in tunnel (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #10678-6 Early tunnel with technician (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #6711-3-12 Correction coils on synchrotron, R. Litauer (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #6711-3-6, -7 Control electronics in tunnel, R. Litauer (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Commerical and Illustrative Photo C. Hadley Smith #69-9-19-4, -10, -16, -24 Linac stack with L. Tunison and others (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - #6871-23-8, -10, -16, -29, -33 “An electron’s eye view of a copper foil target inside synchrotron ...” (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - #6871-24-11, -14 “electron eye view of tunnel” (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Commercial and Illustrative Photo C. Hadley Smith (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - #69-12-11-1.....13 Views of Apparatus in L0 Experimental Hall and Beam Line Flare region of tunnel (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Most are numbered by Photo Services, Commercial and Illustrative Photo or Cornell University Photo, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 37-38)
  - Views of Apparatus in L0 Experimental Hall and Synchrotron tunnel, G. Brown, F. Olshevski and others (Box 9, Folder 37-38)
  - L0 Experimental Hall (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Commercial and Illustrative Photo, C. Hadley Smith 10 of LAME Experiment, 2 of CLASP Experiment, 1 of WAB Experiment, 2 of DECO Experiment, 1969, 1974, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Unlabeled closeup of photomultiplier array (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Illustrative Photography, C. Hadley Smith 78-1-30-1, 78-3-3-5, -6, -7, -8, -9, -10, -11, -12 Views of power supply for synchrotron steering coils (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Jerry Bragstad, Berkeley, CA, #6515-8, -9 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Views of a model of Wilson Lab (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Views of Butler Building, 1965-10-18 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - 10 GeV Tunnel and Site Work (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - Contractor Taylor Bros. (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - A and E Wm Brobeck and Associates (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-8 Driveway Bridge Foundation, 1965-08-02 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-11 New Driveway Bridge, 1965-09-03 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-14 Driveway Bridge, 1965-10-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-15 Creek and Utility Pipe, 1965-10-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-19 Tunnel entrance- railroad track, 1965-10-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-22 Parking lot, creek, Polo field, 1965-10-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-31 Bridge, creek and dam at road entrance, 1965-12-02 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-42 same from downstream, 1966-01-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10677-43 Top of dam, 1966-01-04 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10678-5 Butler Building, 1965-07-16 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10767-4 Vacuum Equipment in entrance to tunnel, 1966-01-19 (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - #10767-5 same subject (Box 9, Folder 43-44)
  - Early Views of Synchrotron Control Room, Experimental Counting Room (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Cornell Univ. Photo #6871-11-4, -17, -19, -22, -25A, #6871-12-13, #6871-13-23, #6871-27-37, #6871-29-8, -11 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Various Views of Control Room (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Construction related to the CLEO pit in L0 experimental hall. A sign reads “Vista Point LAKE TIGNER ELEVATION 900 ft.” (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Color view of Jungle Gym RF structure (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Synchrotron RF equipment (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Synchrotron RF structures, J. Brauley (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Large superconducting RF cavities and cryostats (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Cutting Bus Bars in tunnel, 1978-03-01 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - SE corner of LOE experimental hall, 1978-03-01 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Physics Staff posing on steps: Labeled: R. French, D. Hatfield, B. Meeds, F. Brown, N. Szabo, J. Miner, C. Steckler, L. Margosian, P. Lepage, A. Giambattista, V. Koturel, P. Krassicky, 2000-10-12 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - University of Rochester Group Photo at Seventh Annual Conference on High Energy Nuclear Physics, Many names hand printed on a second copy, 1957-04-15-1957-04-19 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Control Room Celebration for CESR POSITRONS Many staff faces, 1979-05-28 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Control Room Celebration for 10 GeV, Many staff faces (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Blowup of face in newspaper, maybe early H.Bethe (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - RR Wilson and R. Litauer in tunnel (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - RR Wilson on bicycle in tunnel (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Statue in desk-coper colored, twisted form (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Two views of CESR ring drawn on campus photo, 2000-06-08 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Aerial view of Fermilab (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fermilab tunnel and magnets (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Fermilab double quadrupole (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - First superconducting cavity for CESR test, parts and assembly, J. Kirchgessner (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Various Muffin Tin RF Superconducting Cavities, no dates (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Various elliptical RF Superconducting Cavities, no dates, H. Padamsee, R. Sundelin (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
  - Various elliptical SRF Cavities, one labeled “Cornell 5-cell elliptical cavity pair for CEBAF”, no dates (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Cryostats for SRF Cavities, J. Kirchgessner, C. Chaffey, 1978-06-24 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - one envelope from Meyer Tool of CESR SRF Cryostat, 1993-06-24 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Large SRF Cavities, Some are the CESR Cavity, Some are from other labs (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - SRF special items and instrumentation (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - CUSB I Experiment (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Inner Detector for CLEO III, parts and assembly, J. Cherwinka (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - CLEO Drawing (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Copper RF Cavities (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - L0 Experimental hall with technician (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Synchrotron Table 18 closeup (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - CLEO Drift Chamber and electronics (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - CLEO CsI Crystal (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - CLEO I Detector Line Drawings (Box 10, Folder 17-21)
  - Corn. Photo Services 12805-14L CLEO I Octant Assembly (Box 10, Folder 17-21)
  - CLEO I Construction of component parts of the detector (Box 10, Folder 17-21)
  - CESR Electrostatic Separator, various stages of construction, R. Lobdell, D. Morse, J. Kirchgessner, and others, no date (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Drawings of CLEO II (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Test Beam Apparatus, envelope dated August 1990 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Muon Chambers CLEO II Cosmic Ray Testing Station, 1991-09-06 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - CLEO II During Assembly (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Inside CLEO II View of end of drift chamber and inner detector (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Loading CsI Crystals on truck at Newman Lab (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Corn. Univ. photo 850403-1-4A, -7A, 12A, 26A, -31A (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Electronics and testing CsI Crystals (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - 850403-2-15A, -18A, -19A, -20A, 22A, -31A, -34A (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Stringing the CLEO II Drift Chamber (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - CHESS Apparatus, 1984-02 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - CHESS Insertion Magnet, Spectra Technology (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Various material (Box 11-18)
  Includes clippings, photos, publications, etc..
  - Mostly apparatus, diagrams. Many are deteriorated dark gray. One of a 10-GeV synchrotron experiment, 1969-03 (Box 11)
  - Mostly apparatus, diagrams. Many are deteriorated dark gray. One dated April 1971 of Wilson Laboratory sign, 1971-04 (Box 11)
  - See Photos Index in Box 14 (Box 11)
  - No dates, one labeled “typical rho production experiment”, Many are deteriorated dark gray (Box 11)
  - A crane holding some apparatus, Many are deteriorated dark gray., 1997-10-30 (Box 11)
  - Apparatus, Diagrams, Tables, Floor Plans, One labeled Princeton-Penn Accelerator (Box 11)
  - Magnet Drawings, Floor Plans (Box 11)
  - No date. Lecture slides of a talk about results from an electron spectrometer experiment (Box 11)
  - “A Visit to the Wilson Laboratory, Cornell University” - (Box 11)
  - An Ithaca College Pro. Unit Production (Box 11)
  - Superconducting and copper RF Apparatus. These are old Microsoft format files and have been reformatted onto a CD of jpg files in January 2011, 1979-05-28 (Box 11)
  - This is a catch-all of collections of all sorts. Some labels: SYNAC, 10-GeV, Cornell Univ. Photos. Some names: Ron Prouty, J. Kandaswamy, Stuart Henderson, Dave Morse, Jim Fast, 1955, 1978, 1991, 1993, 1995 (Box 11)
  - 35 2 x 2 in. slides in cardboard 3 x 4 lantern slide mounts. They are marked with Photo Index numbers (see Box 14) (Box 11)
  - Collection returned by “Bridget”, 1993-06 (Box 11)
  - Envelop by G. Trutt of apparatus and staff at the Coil Factory at Hi-Volt Lab (Box 11)
  - Envelop of 10-GeV Wilson laboratory construction and early views, no labels or dates (Box 11)
  - Envelopes of items with Photo Index numbers (see Box 14) (Box 11)
  - Pictures of T. Allen, B. J., Ray Helmke, Persis Drell with Photo Index numbers (see Box 14) (Box 11)
  - About 350 photos, unlabeled (Box 11)
  - Apparatus and some people (Box 11)
  - Pictures of Gordon Brown (Box 11)
  - Magnet laminations, Group Photo, Campus Views, SRF cavities, C Firenze, N. Mistry with Photo Index numbers (see Box 14) (Box 11)
  - Envelopes of film 303146 (12 photos)and 303147 (9 photos), each with a CD containing jpeg files of the Chuck McNeil retirement celebration party in Wilson Lab Commons, 2003-02-21 (Box 11)
  - Cornell Sun, Cornell Chronicle, 1948, 1952, 1965, 1968, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 10 GeV control room party celebrating first success, 1974-04 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 20-TeV Workshop, People at conference, 1983-04 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Many kinds of subjects: apparatus, people. Many dates (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - IBM 1828 Computer, E. Thorndike, Cornell University Photo (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 68711-4-7A (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - E. Thorndike, L. Hand - 6871-10-5 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - E. Thorndike - 6871-10-9, 6871-10-20 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - L0 Experimental Hall: Illustrative Photography 62-12-11-9 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CLEO II View from above (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CLEO II Drift Chamber (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CLEO II Detector (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CLEO II Detector being assembled in Pit: B. McDaniel (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - B. Gittleman, E. Nordberg (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cutaway Drawing of Wilson Lab Building and Tunnel (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Plan of Cornell 10 GeV Synchrotron: Cornell Office of (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Public Information (COPI) (3) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Linac Stack, two people: COPI (4) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - William Woodward surveying: COPI (5) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - R. Matyas on bicycle in tunnel: COPI (6) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Internal view of synchrotron magnet with reflections: (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - COPI (8) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Target inside vacuum chamber: COPI (9) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - L0 Experimental Hall, two people: COPI (10) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Two Techs on bicycles in tunnel: COPI (11) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - H. Edwards in birds eye view of control room: COPI (12) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - R. Litauer inspecting synchrotron steering coil: COPI (7) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - BNL Summer School – Padamsee- Superconducting RF Cavities and Apparatus, Indexed 066 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Copper RF Cavities and Cryostats (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - SRF cavities and other apparatus Index ref. 066, 1972, 1978, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Prototype CESR Christmas cards, CHESS Brochure, RR Wilson Obituary, Nature 23, 2000-03 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Lepton-Photon Brochure, 1993-08 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ken Wilson – Nobel Prize Celebration, many faculty faces, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Portraits of B. D. McDaniel (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Synchro-Art Various artistic views of apparatus (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous items such as 300 GeV accelerator, Newman Lab; CLEO I, CLEO II Detector; DR II; RF and SRF Structures; posed personnel; campus view; M. Tigner portrait; B. McDaniel and RR Wilson; K. Berkelman; S. Gray; B. J.; D. Widger (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Celebration in honor of B. McDaniel (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Cornell University Photography 36/01-A-19a: H. Edwards and D. Edwards in formal attire (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 36/01-A-17a: B. McDaniel, H. Edwards, D. Edwards, D. Rubin, M. Tigner in formal attire (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 36/01-A-15a: all above and University officials (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - B. McDaniel portrait, and email from National Acadamies Press (rejecting this photo for memorial), 2004-05 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Cornell University Photography contact sheets- 36/01B, 37/0: (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - 2.2 Gev Synchrotron in background, Formal posed picture with RR Wilson seated in foreground and staff standing behind, no date (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - H. Bethe and B. McDaniel on bicycles in 10 GeV Synchrotron Tunnel: no date (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Christmas Party, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Letters RR Wilson Biographical Material, Bibliography, 1972, 1973, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Wilson Laboratory Floor Plans (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Berkeley Daily News: “UC Unveils World’s most Powerful Atom-Smasher”, 1949-02-04 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Syracuse Post Standard: “Oppie and the A-Bomb”, 1946-10-20 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Original mock-up copy of CESR Booklet (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Old Newman Lab Apparatus (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Various personnel faces at Celebration/Symposium: (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - McDaniel, Tigner, Kirchgessner, Mistry, Litauer, Berkelman, Sadoff, Doney, Gittleman, Bethe, Andrews (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Apparatus (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Various unrelated subjects: Lecture notes on nuclear power, Beam line drawings, Accelerator performance, CESR Ring, ITEP hugh apparatus (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Electron Synchrotron- Set of 12 prints and descriptions from prototype of early brochure: stamped Office of Public Information (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Service Improvement/Cost Reduction Award Program-1981 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Service Improvement/Cost Reduction Award Program-1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Cost Reduction Incentive Award, 1984, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - R. Feynman (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Machine shop setting, CNC milling machine “Mazak” with large ring, (Maybe part of dE/dx detector for CLEO III) (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Campus overview (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Unlabeled slides (Box 12, Folder 31-35)
  - This is a picture gallery of slides available for talks (both 2 x 3 and 35 mm) Includes: Mock-Up, Building Construction, Tunnel, Magnet, L0, L3, Ring and Quadrupole, Linac, Synac, Multiplex, Vacuum Pump, 10-GeV Experiments, Miscellaneous, 2.2 GeV, Popular Lectures, Binder (Box 12)
  - Various Distinguished Physicists whose portraits hang on the walls of Newman Laboratory: CN Yang, CS Wu, TD Lee, RR Wilson, Hans Bethe, KG Wilson, JR Openheimer, EO Lawrence, VF Weisskopf, W Pauli, E Fermi, A Einstein, HA Lorentz, Neils Bohr, E Rutherford, E Saltpeter, R Feynman (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 063 Injection Apparatus (5) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 063 (4) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 066 SRF Apparatus (27) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 066 (10) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 067 (1) Miscellaneous: CERN beam line apparatus (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - RR Wilson at Princeton and Los Alamos with J. DeWire, B. McDaniel, EO Lawrence (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - RR Wilson and Jane Wilson Horseback at Los Alamos (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Trinity Site (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letter Fermilab, 1994-01-25 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letter Fermilab, 80th birthday celebration and old photos, 1993-11-11 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - More old photos about RR Wilson’s 80th celebration (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - RR Wilson related material: Pre-Cornell settings, early Cornell, later Cornell (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Prints of apparatus not connected to RR Wilson, one of E. Thorndike (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - R. Litauer and Synchrotron Steering Coil (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Feedback Kicker (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Survey Telescope through hole in wall: (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cornell University Photo 6871-19-17 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Vacuum Chamber: (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Photo Science Studios 8728-3 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - End View drawing of synchrotron magnet (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - End view of RF structure (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Drawing of Wilson Lab building (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Campus views with Synchrotron tunnel superimposed (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - RR Wilson and horse at Los Alamos (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - RR Wilson and Jane at Berkeley (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - CLEO II Drift Chamber stringing operation with techs (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - CLEO dE/dX chamber assembly operation with techs (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - CLEO II Group photo: Cornell University Photo 816/99 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Unlabeled old photos of apparatus and control room, Newman Lab construction, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1953-1954 Synchrotron at Newman Lab: Photo Science Studios 6612-8, 77138-A, 6752-A,C, 7316, 9499 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Details of Pole Tip, Gradient Coil, Vacuum system (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Two paintings of the electron synchrotron (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Three ring binder containing an index of the photo albums in the collection. (Box 14)
    Includes summary pages listing File Number, Cross Reference, N P S T where N-Negative, P-Print, S-Slide, T-Transparency, PS PhotoServices, VS Visual Services, HS Hadley Smith and the following larger sections:
    1 Newman Laboratory: The Beginning
    10 300-MeV
    20 1.4-GeV
    30 2.2-GeV
    40 C-Bug (Cosmic Ray, Balloon, E170)
    50 10-GeV (Building Construction)
    51 10-GeV (Tunnel Construction)
    52 10-GeV (Linac)
    53 10-GeV (Magnets)
    54 10-GeV (Electronics)
    55 10-GeV (Experiments)
    56 10-GeV (Miscellaneous)
    57 10-GeV (RF)
    60 CESR (Building Construction)
    61 CESR (Assembly)
    62 CESR (Magnets)
    63 CESR (Injection)
    64 CESR (Vacuum)
    65 CESR (RF)
    66 CESR (Superconducting RF)
    67 CESR (Miscellaneous)
    70 CLEO I (Mechanical)
    71 CLEO I (Electronics)
    80 CLEO II (Mechanical)
    81 CLEO II (Electronics)
    82 CLEO III (Mechanical)
    83 CLEO III (Electronics)
    90 Mini-Beta
    100 Micro-Beta
    110 CHESS
    120 CUSB
    130 Achievements
    131 Symposiums, Conferences, Meeting, etc.
    132 Education / Outreach
    140 Personnel
    150 Social Functions
    160 Miscellaneous / General
    161 General Physics
    162 Public Relations
    170 B-Factory
  - 062-CESR (Magnets), 1992-07, 1993-07, 1994-01 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 063-CESR (Injection) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 065-CESR (RF), 1988-07, 1990-02, 1992-11 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 066-CESR (Superconducting RF) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 066-CESR (SRF), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 067-CESR (Miscellaneous), 1990-07, 1992-11, 1993-04, 1993-05, 1993-12, 1994-01 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 080-CLEO II (Mechanical) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 110-CHESS, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 120-CUSB, 1989-10, 1989-12, 1990-01, 1990-02 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 130 Achievements, 1980-04 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The 25th anniversary of 10GeV, 1992-11 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 131-Symposiums, conferences, meetings, 1982-01, 1990-07, 1992-09 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 140-Personnel, 1985, 1987-1989, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 150-Social Functions, 1979-04, 1980-04, 1990-07 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 150-Social Functions-Service Awards, 1991-09, 1992-01, 1992-09 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - A large (about 1 m) vessel for cryogenics (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - 160-Miscellaneous/General, 1987-1993 (Box 15, Folder 15-17)
  - 161-General Physics, 1992-10 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - 170-B-Factory, 1992-04, 1993-05, 1993-06 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Photos from R. Bower, 1970-1983 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - 040-C-Bug (Cosmic Ray) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 060-CESR (building construction) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 062-CESR (Magnets) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 063-CESR (Injection) (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 064-CESR (Vacuum) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 065-CESR (RF) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 066-CESR (SRF) (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
  - 067-CESR (Miscellaneous) (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 070-CLEO I (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 080-CLEO II (Box 16, Folder 11-16)
  - 081-CLEO II (Electronics) (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - 090 Mini Beta (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - 100-Micro Beta (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - 110- CHESS (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - 120-CUSB (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - 140-Personnel (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - 150-Social Functions (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - 160-Miscellaneous/General (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - 162-Public Relations (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - VS-6711-1...6 Early 10-GeV construction (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - VS-6832-1...3 Counting Room, Tunnel (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - VS-6857-1-11A, 33A Robert Wilson, Boyce McDaniel (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - VS-6871-26-4 Boyce McDaniel and apparatus (Box 16, Folder 26)